Guide to the Daniel Rubin Papers TAM.657
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: Post-1991 Communist Party Split, 1991-2015; 37 Linear Feet in 77 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 4 cassette boxes; 71 audiocassettes; 2.54 Gigabytes in 1030 computer files
  - Introduction to Marxism, 1982-1996 (Box 193, Folder 13-14)
  - Is Marxism Necessary?: Education, 2001-2010 (Box 194, Folder 1)
  - Is Marxism Necessary for Social Progress and Socialism?, undated (Box 194, Folder 2)
  - Italian Communist Party, etc., 1997 (Box 194, Folder 3)
  - Ivins, Molly, 2007-2008; TW_TAM_657_ER_23
  - Jackson, James: Memorial, 2007, 2013; TW_TAM_657_ER_24
  - Jackson, James and Esther Biographies, 2001 (Box 194, Folder 4)
  - Jackson, James and Esther Wills, 2007 (Box 194, Folder 5)
  - Jackson, Jim and Jim Steele, 1993 June 21 (Box 238, Cassette 200)
  - Jewish Commission: Hashomer Hatzair and CPUSA Meeting: Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 194, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Currents: Annotated Issues, 1975-1987 (Box 194, Folder 7-8)
  - Jewish Currents: Annotated Issues, 1988-1995 (Box 195, Folder 1-4)
  - Jewish Issues and Israel: Collected Ephemera, 1999-2006 (Box 195, Folder 5-7)
  - Jewish Issues: Collected Ephemera: Workmen's Circle, 2002-2006 (Box 196, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Issues: Essay on Morris Schappes by Gene Schwartz, 2004 (Box 196, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Lists, 2008-2009 (Box 196, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Organizations, 2008-2009 (Box 196, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Question, 1998-2006 (Box 196, Folder 5-7)
  - Jewish Question: Annotated Articles, undated (Box 196, Folder 8-10)
  - Jewish Question: Collected Articles, 2007 (Box 197, Folder 1-2)
  - Jewish Question: Collected Flyers and Periodicals, 2006-2008 (Box 197, Folder 3-7)
  - Jewish Question: Collected Periodicals, 2006-2007 (Box 198, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Question: Correspondence, 2007 (Box 198, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Question: Jews in the Labor Movement, 2006 (Box 198, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Question: Materials to Read and Keep, 2006 (Box 198, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Question: Yakut Moreshet Holocaust Documentation and Research, 2004 (Box 198, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Writings #1, 2003-2005 (Box 198, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Work, 2004-2007 (Box 198, Folder 7, Box 199, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Work: Collected Articles, 2006-2007 (Box 199, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Work: Correspondence and Collected Ephemera, 2002-2003 (Box 199, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Work: Correspondence, Reports and Articles, 2006 (Box 199, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Work: Guy Ben-Dror, 2004-2005 (Box 199, Folder 5-6)
  - Jewish Work: Obama and Rosenbergs, 2008 (Box 200, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Work: Political Assessment of the US Jews, 2007-2008, 2014
    - Paper Materials (Box 200, Folder 2)
    - Digital Materials, TW_TAM_657_ER_25
  - Jewish Work: Theoretical, 2007 (Box 200, Folder 3)
  - Jews and Socialism: Annotated Articles, circa 1970s (Box 200, Folder 4-6)
  - Jews and Israel: Annotated Articles, circa 1960s-2000s (Box 200, Folder 7)
  - Labor, 1995-2005 (Box 200, Folder 8-9)
  - Labor Paper, 2003 (Box 200, Folder 10)
  - Labor Party, 1998-2001 (Box 200, Folder 11-12)
  - Labor Research Association, undated (Box 201, Folder 1)
  - Latino Peoples in United States, 1990-1997 (Box 201, Folder 2)
  - Left: Others, 1997 (Box 201, Folder 3-4)
  - Left Forum, 2010 (Box 201, Folder 5)
  - Left Forum: Science and Society Panels Program, 2012 (Box 201, Folder 6)
  - Leftists - David Silver, 2001 (Box 201, Folder 7)
  - Legal: CPUSA v. 522 Valencia, Inc.: Case Files, 1993, 1995 (Box 201, Folder 8)
  - Legal: CPUSA v. Aptheker, Linton, Rubin: Continued Examination Before Trial (July 1st), 1994 (Box 201, Folder 9)
  - Legal: CPUSA v. Aptheker, Linton, Rubin: Continued Examination Before Trial (July 12th), 1994 (Box 201, Folder 10)
  - Legal: CPUSA v. Aptheker, Linton, Rubin: Continued Examination Before Trial (September 29th), 1994 (Box 201, Folder 11)
  - Legal: CPUSA v. Aptheker, Linton, Rubin: Depositions, 1995 (Box 201, Folder 12)
  - Legal: CPUSA v. Aptheker, Linton, Rubin: Examination Before Trial of Rubin, 1994 (Box 201, Folder 13)
  - Legal: CPUSA v. Aptheker, Linton, Rubin: Fact and Editorial Material on Both Cases, 1978, 1990 (Box 201, Folder 14)
  - Legal: CPUSA v. Aptheker, Linton, Rubin: Notes on Strategy for Cases, undated (Box 201, Folder 15)
  - Legal: CPUSA v. Aptheker, Linton, Rubin: Plans for Questioning in Deposition, 1995 (Box 201, Folder 16)
  - Legal: CPUSA v. Aptheker, Linton, Rubin: Research, 1993 (Box 202, Folder 1)
  - Legal: Dorothy Rubin Research on CPUSA Lawsuits, 1990-1993 (Box 202, Folder 2)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Aptheker Deposition, 1995 (Box 202, Folder 3)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Case Notes and Correspondence, 1992 (Box 202, Folder 4)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Case Notes and Defendant's Reply, 1995 (Box 202, Folder 5)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Correspondence about Aptheker Deposition, 1993-1995 (Box 202, Folder 6)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Deposition Materials, 1993 (Box 202, Folder 7)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Examination Before Trial of Linton, 1991 (Box 202, Folder 8)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Examination Before Trial of Perlin, 1993 (Box 202, Folder 9)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Examination Before Trial of Rubin, 1991 (Box 202, Folder 10-11)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Notes About and Response to the Case, 1992 (Box 202, Folder 12)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Pat Barile Deposition, 1995 (Box 202, Folder 13)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Possible Depositions, 1995 (Box 202, Folder 14)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Pre-Trial Documents, Depositions, and Settlements, 1990-1992 (Box 202, Folder 15)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Rubin Deposition Corrections, 1994 (Box 202, Folder 16)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Verified Answers and Affirmation Documents, 1992 (Box 202, Folder 17)
  - Legal: Friedenberg: Will, Affidavits, and Other Case Files, 1992 (Box 203, Folder 1)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Appeal, 1995 (Box 203, Folder 2)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Appellate Court Decision, 1995 (Box 203, Folder 3)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Becchetti Deposition Notes, 1992 (Box 203, Folder 4)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Becchetti Estoppel, 1993 (Box 203, Folder 5)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Chronology on Case, 1995 (Box 203, Folder 6)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Constructive Law Trust and Fact, 1993 (Box 203, Folder 7)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Correspondence and Will, 1966, 1998 (Box 203, Folder 8)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: "Dear Friend" Support Mailings for Aptheker, Linton, Rubin, 1995 (Box 203, Folder 9)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Examination Before Trial of Rubin, 1995 (Box 203, Folder 10-11)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Freedman Account, Depositions, Financial Statements, 1992 (Box 204, Folder 1-2)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Law Documents and Affidavit, 1994 (Box 204, Folder 3)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Legal Expenses and Lawyers, 1997 (Box 204, Folder 4)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Motion to Dismiss, 1994 (Box 204, Folder 5)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Notes and Memorandum of Law of Respondent, 1993 (Box 204, Folder 6)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Order to Report to Examination Before Trial for Rubin, 1995 (Box 204, Folder 7)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Petition and Answer of Respondent, 1994 (Box 204, Folder 8)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Petitioner's Documents, 1994 (Box 204, Folder 9)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Research, 1993 (Box 204, Folder 10)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Research Materials, 1994 (Box 204, Folder 11)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Settlement of Cases, 1996-1999 (Box 204, Folder 12)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Summary Judgement Motion, 1994 (Box 204, Folder 13)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: Will and Other Case Files, 1966, 1995 (Box 205, Folder 1)
  - Legal: Trachtenberg: "The Wrong Enemy" Response to People's Weekly World, 1997 (Box 205, Folder 2-4)
  - Linton: Booking and Budget, 1996 (Box 205, Folder 5)
  - Linton: Irrevocable Trust Deposit Tickets, 2001 (Box 205, Folder 6)
  - Linton: Management of Assets, 1996 (Box 205, Folder 7)
  - Linton: Southwest Bell - Southwestern Bell Corporation, 1996 (Box 205, Folder 8)
  - Linton: State Street Research, 1999 (Box 205, Folder 9)
  - Linton: Trust Bank Statements, 2002 (Box 205, Folder 10)
  - Linton: Will, Trust Agreement, Power of Attorney, 2004 (Box 205, Folder 11)
  - Lists for Communist Party, 1991-1994, 2001 (Box 205, Folder 12)
  - Letters to and from Lowenfells, Dolsen, 1959, 1973, 2005 (Box 205, Folder 13)
  - Magil, Abe Materials, 2003-2009 (Box 206, Folder 1)
  - Mandela, Nelson: Photographs, 2006; TW_TAM_657_ER_28
  - Marilyn on South Africa; Discussion on Socialism, 1997 February 23 (Box 237, Cassette 169)
  - Martin Luther King Jr. Day: Photographs, 2005; TW_TAM_657_ER_26
  - Marx, Engels and Lenin Book, undated (Box 206, Folder 2)
  - Marx, Lenin, Engels Excerpts, 2004 (Box 206, Folder 3)
  - Marx-Lenin Quotes, 2000 (Box 206, Folder 4-5)
  - Marxism-Leninism, undated (Box 206, Folder 6)
  - Marxist Discussion Group, 1996-1998 (Box 206, Folder 7)
  - Marxist Educational Press Publications and Other Materials, 1990-1992 (Box 206, Folder 8)
  - Marxist Methodology, 2000 (Box 206, Folder 9)
  - Marxist Methodology: MDG, 2000 May 19 (Box 236, Cassette 118-119)
  - Marxist Theory, 1999 (Box 206, Folder 10)
  - Mideast, 2002 (Box 206, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1996 (Box 207, Folder 1)
  - Monthly Review, undated (Box 207, Folder 2)
  - Moskowitz, Larry: Printed Letter, 1998 (Box 207, Folder 3)
  - Nagin, Rick, 2012; TW_TAM_657_ER_27
  - National Politics: Elections: General, 2011-2012 (Box 207, Folder 4)
  - Nature, Society, and Thoughts: Articles for Marquit, 1992-1993 (Box 207, Folder 5-6)
  - New Party Materials, 1997-2001 (Box 207, Folder 7-8)
  - National Politics: Elections: General, 2010 (Box 207, Folder 9)
  - New York: Analysis, 1993-1994 (Box 207, Folder 10)
  - New York: Elections, 2006-2013 (Box 207, Folder 11-13)
  - New York: Elections: Barbaro Campaign, 2004 (Box 207, Folder 14)
  - New York: Elections: Batson, Bill, 2006 (Box 207, Folder 15)
  - New York: Elections: Bishop, Tim and Others, 2010 (Box 208, Folder 1)
  - New York: Elections: General, 2006-2012 (Box 208, Folder 2-6)
  - New York: Elections: Jackson, Diskin, Steele, Rubin, 1993 November 10 (Box 238, Cassette 202)
  - New York: Elections: James, Letitia: Research, 2009 (Box 208, Folder 7)
  - New York: Elections: James Campaign, 2005 (Box 208, Folder 8)
  - New York: Elections: Liu, John, 2009 (Box 208, Folder 9)
  - New York: Elections: Liu, John: Volunteer Lists (Restricted), 2009 (Box 241, Folder 3)
    Access to folder 3 is restricted until 2068.
  - New York: Elections: Murphy, Mark, 2010 (Box 208, Folder 10)
  - New York: Elections: Owens, Chris, 2005-2006 (Box 208, Folder 11-12)
  - New York: Elections: Owens, Chris, 2005-2006 (Box 209, Folder 1-5)
  - New York: Elections: Owens, Chris: Ads, 2006 July-August (Box 209, Folder 6)
  - New York: Elections: Owens, Chris: Before Aug 15, 2006 (Box 209, Folder 7)
  - New York: Elections: Owens, Chris: Better World Awards, 2006 (Box 209, Folder 8)
  - New York: Elections: Owens, Chris: Owens Campaign, 2006 (Box 209, Folder 9)
  - New York: Elections: Skaller, Josh, 2009 (Box 209, Folder 10)
  - New York: Elections: Thompson, Bill, 2009 (Box 209, Folder 11)
  - New York: Elections: Yasky, David, 2006 (Box 209, Folder 12)
  - New York: Marxist School: Brecht Forum, 1991 (Box 210, Folder 1)
  - New York: Transit, 2005 (Box 210, Folder 2-4)
  - New York City: Document Research, 1993-1994 (Box 210, Folder 5-6)
  - New York City: Elections, 2003 (Box 210, Folder 7)
  - New York City: Research, 1993 (Box 210, Folder 8)
  - New York City: Research, 1993-1994 (Box 211, Folder 1)
  - Nichter, Matt: Correspondence, 2007 (Box 211, Folder 2)
  - Nichter, Matt: "The Old Left and the Rise of the Civil Rights Movement", 2005-2006 (Box 211, Folder 3)
  - Notes, Outlines, Drafts, and Short Essays, 2007-2015; TW_TAM_657_ER_29
  - November 6, 2012 and Racism (Box 211, Folder 4)
  - Outline of The Book, undated (Box 211, Folder 5)
  - Owens, Major: Photographs, 2005-2006; TW_TAM_657_ER_30
  - Patrinos, Sandy and Jim Williams, 1999-2000 (Box 211, Folder 6)
  - Peace and International Meeting, 2004-2005 (Box 211, Folder 7)
  - Peace News, 2004 (Box 211, Folder 8)
  - Pearson, Theodore, 1999, 2002 (Box 211, Folder 9-10)
  - People's Party, 2000 (Box 211, Folder 11)
  - People's Weekly World Articles by Daniel Rubin, 2003 (Box 212, Folder 1)
  - People's Weekly World Forum Planning, 2009 (Box 211, Folder 12)
  - People's Weekly World Honorees, 2009 (Box 211, Folder 13)
  - People's Weekly World and Political Affairs, 2003 (Box 211, Folder 14)
  - Personal Correspondence, 2007-2008 (Box 211, Folder 15)
  - Personal Documents/Materials, 2007-2009 (Box 212, Folder 2-3)
  - Pietaro, John: Correspondence, 2010 (Box 212, Folder 4)
  - Political Action: Elections: General, 2007 (Box 212, Folder 5)
  - Political Affairs, undated (Box 212, Folder 6)
  - Politicians, Political Events, and Ceremonies -- Photographs, 2005-2006; TW_TAM_657_ER_31
  - Public Employees Rally: New York Central Labor Council, 2014 (Box 212, Folder 7)
  - Puerto Rican Question, 1999 (Box 212, Folder 8)
  - Racial and National Oppression and Women, 2008 (Box 212, Folder 9)
  - Rainbow Coalition, 1991-1992 (Box 212, Folder 10)
  - Reading: Committees of Correspondence Material, 1992 (Box 212, Folder 11)
  - Recruiting Drive, 2003 (Box 212, Folder 12)
  - Report on Social Security, 2005 (Box 212, Folder 13)
  - Schafner, Jay, 2002 (Box 212, Folder 14)
  - Schafner, Jay: Case, 1991 (Box 212, Folder 15)
  - Smith Act, 1996 (Box 212, Folder 16)
  - Smith, Michael, 1993-1994 (Box 212, Folder 17)
  - Social Democracy, 2000 (Box 212, Folder 18)
  - Social Democracy, 2001 January 7 (Box 236, Cassette 134-135)
  - Socialism, 1997 March 16 (Box 236, Cassette 136-137)
  - Socialism: Collected Articles, 1970-2001 (Box 213, Folder 1)
  - Socialism: Sam Webb Writings, 2005 (Box 213, Folder 2-3)
  - Socialism / Dover, Michael A., 1993-1994 (Box 213, Folder 4)
  - Socialism and Organization, 1998 (Box 213, Folder 5)
  - Socialist Materials Revived and Opinions Given, 1997 (Box 213, Folder 6)
  - Socialist Party USA and Moderate Socialists, 1998 (Box 213, Folder 7)
  - Socialist Scholars Conference, 1999 (Box 213, Folder 8)
  - Solidarity and Labor Notes, 1999 (Box 213, Folder 9)
  - South Africa, 1998-1999 (Box 213, Folder 10-11)
  - South African Communist Party, 1997 (Box 213, Folder 12)
  - State and Democracy: Rogue R. Opens; MDG, 1998 March 14 (Box 236, Cassette 129-130)
  - Steele on CBC Conference, 1994 October 12 (Box 237, Cassette 168)
  - Steele, Jim and Jim Jackson: Tape 2, 1992 March 27 (Box 238, Cassette 198)
  - Steffens, Dorothy, 1999 (Box 213, Folder 13)
  - Strategy: MDG, 1997 June 7 (Box 236, Cassette 112-113)
  - Strategy and Tactics: MDG, 1998 July 11 (Box 236, Cassette 114-115)
  - Strategy and Tactics: Session #1, undated (Box 236, Cassette 121-122)
  - Strategy and Tactics: The Theory, History and Possible Application of, to the US, 1998-1999 (Box 213, Folder 14)
  - Strategy and Tactics for Socialism in the USA, 1998-1999 (Box 214, Folder 1-3)
  - Students, 1998-2001 (Box 214, Folder 4)
  - Soviet Union Basic Documents and International Movement, 1991-1993 (Box 214, Folder 5)
  - Suit on Car Accident: Rose, Dot, 1997 (Box 214, Folder 6)
  - Tamiment Library, 1992 (Box 214, Folder 7)
  - Terrorism, 2002 (Box 214, Folder 8)
  - Transition to Socialism in United States, 2002 (Box 214, Folder 9)
  - Union, 1992-1994 (Box 214, Folder 10)
  - United for Peace and Justice: Anti-War March: Lists, 2003-2004 (Box 214, Folder 11-12)
  - United for Peace and Justice: Anti-War March: Contacts, 2003 (Box 215, Folder 1)
  - United for Peace and Justice Letters and Flyers (Extras), 2002-2003 (Box 215, Folder 2)
  - Unity for Peace, Democracy, Jobs and Equality Program, 2005-2006 (Box 215, Folder 3-5)
  - US Communist Party History, 1996 (Box 215, Folder 6)
  - US Elections: Jim Steele Opens, Discussion, 1996 November 24 (Box 238, Cassette 203)
  - Vacation Reading, 1992 (Box 215, Folder 7)
  - Value Theory: Clark Opens; MDG, 1998 January 11 (Box 236, Cassette 131-132)
  - Vietnam Teach-In, 2000 (Box 215, Folder 8)
  - The Volunteer (Journal of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade), 1999, 2000 (Box 215, Folder 9)
  - Webber, Sam, 2001 (Box 215, Folder 10)
  - Welch, Rebecca: Correspondence, 2007-2009 (Box 215, Folder 11)
  - What Happened to Socialism, 1994 (Box 216, Folder 1-2)
  - Why the Communist Party Grew and Declined: Lou Diskin, Jim Jackson, 1993 March 27 (Box 237, Cassette 167)
  - Winston, Henry: 100th Anniversary Tribute Booklet and Program, 2012 (Box 216, Folder 3)
  - Winston, Henry: Memorial Event, 2011-2012
    - Paper Materials (Box 216, Folder 4-5)
    - Digital Materials, TW_TAM_657_ER_33
  - Winston, Henry: Memorial Event: Appreciation Texts, 2012 (Box 216, Folder 6)
  - Winston, Henry: Memorial Event: Appreciation Texts, 2012 (Box 217, Folder 1)
  - Women's Equality, 1995 (Box 217, Folder 2)
  - Women's Question (News Clippings), undated (Box 217, Folder 3)
  - Working Class: Jim Jackson: Tape 1, 1993 September 22 (Box 237, Cassette 147)
  - Working Class and CPUSA: Tape 2, 1993 September 22 (Box 237, Cassette 148)
  - Working Class: Jay S. Opens, 1997 November 22 (Box 237, Cassette 149)
  - Working Class: Discussion continued, 1997 November 22 (Box 237, Cassette 150)
  - The World Balance of Forces: A Discussion, 2004 (Box 217, Folder 4)
  - World Relationship of Forces, 2004 (Box 217, Folder 5-6)
  - World War II: Jim Jackson, Jim Steele, Lou Diskin, Danny Rubin, 1993 June 16 (Box 238, Cassette 199)
  - Young Communist League, 2002-2013
    - Paper Materials (Box 217, Folder 7-10)
    - Digital Materials, TW_TAM_657_ER_34
  - Young Communist League: Study Guide Outline by Georgi Dimitrov, undated (Box 218, Folder 1)
  - Young Communist League: Pamphlet, undated (Box 218, Folder 2)
  - Young Communist League: Teaching, 2009 (Box 218, Folder 3)
  - Young Communist League: Youth Education, 2006 (Box 218, Folder 4)
  - Yugoslavia, 1999 (Box 218, Folder 5)